Tamara Lazerka - Full Stack Developer

(415) 231-9021 | lazerkatamara@gmail.com | Github | LinkedIn | Medium | Personal website San Francisco, CA

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Full Stack Software Engineer with 3 years of experience in developing websites and user interface applications. Expert in developing applications using JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS/SCSS and JavaScript frameworks such as React.js. Proficient in resolving bottleneck issues related to performance, cross-browser compatibility, and debugging. Well versed in the best practices of SDLC as well as Agile methodologies. Excellent communication and organizational skills.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend: JavaScript (ES6+), React.js, Redux, TypeScript, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, HTML/CSS, Material-UI, Styled Components, Wordpress

Backend: Python, Rest APIs, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, SQL, Flask, jQuery

Testing: Postman, Jest.

Other: Git, GitHub, Figma, Netlify, Heroku, Docker, Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, UX/UI, Atlassian Suite (Jira, Confluence, BitBucket), Trello

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer, Hack for LA, Remote

09/2023 - Present

- Participated in weekly team meetings to discuss strategies and implementation of various web solutions for projects.
- Reviewed pull requests to ensure that the deliverables are completed and code is clear and maintainable.
- Reviewed and resolved various bugs and implemented features using frontend technologies.
- Worked remotely across teams to complete design issues using Kanban and continuous integration/continuous delivery (CI/CD) methodology.

Full Stack Developer, Independent Projects, Remote

04/2023 - Present

- Developed a currency converter Single Page Application using React and deployed it using GitHub Pages, implementing the Frankfurter API.
- Developed movie ranking Single Page Application using React which allows users to rank, comment, sort and filter movies.
- Contributed to the design and development of a dashboard web application using React and Material UI libraries. Worked closely with a senior developer to create a responsive and user-friendly interface, reusable components, and implement API calls.

Software Engineer Student, Hackbright Academy, Remote

01/2023 - 04/2023

- Engineered a robust full-stack Flask application within an Agile work environment, showcasing proficiency in both front-end and back-end development.
- Pioneered an open-source system that extracts invaluable channel statistics from the Telegram messaging platform, contributing to enhanced user insights and analytics.
- Designed a background service utilizing the Telegram Bot API for seamless and continuous data updates, ensuring real-time information accuracy.
- Spearheaded the integration of an in-browser interactive chart visualization, enhancing data presentation and user experience.
- Actively engaged in daily standup meetings to communicate project progress, fostering a collaborative and transparent work environment.
- Fostered teamwork and knowledge-sharing through pair programming sessions with fellow software engineers, promoting efficient problem-solving and code quality.

Project: Conversation Insights - Github Repo - Open source system for generating valuable channel statistics the Telegram messaging platform.

Technical Integration specialist, Albina Dubois Educational Platform, Ukraine

04/2021 - 10/2022

- Packaged and successfully launched over 5 online training courses.
- Supported the work of several online schools and communities on the GetCourse, Send Pulse platforms.
- Set up different payment services (Stripe, GetCourse, PayPal, Way For Pay, bank accounts integration).
- Set up email lists of different services (Get Response, Send Pulse, BotHelp, GetCourse, smart Sender).
- Moderated and configured live webinars. Debug issues.
- Administered and configured ip phone Zoiper, Zadarma.
- Created a schedule with tasks and controlled deadlines for a 5 person team.
- Created an interactive chatbot for student self-onboarding, facilitating a user-friendly and automated onboarding process.
- Provided technical support to customers, offering assistance with software-related inquiries and resolving issues promptly to ensure reliability of the educational platform.
- Created a landing page for educational courses. Was in charge of setting up the project and creating layout due to design. Used HTML, CSS, JS, and

EDUCATION AND PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Master of Law - Ivan Franko National University, Lviv, Ukraine - 2017 - 2019

Snowflake - Hands On Essentials Data Warehouse - Completed in September 2023

Docker for Absolute Beginners - Hands On - DevOps Udemy, Completed in June 2023

JavaScript (Intermediate) HackerRank, Completed in January 2023

SQL (Intermediate) HackerRank, Completed in October 2022